<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Garbage Collection</title><link href="http://gavin.carothers.name/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://gavin.carothers.name/feeds/self.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://gavin.carothers.name/</id><updated>2009-07-14T20:42:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>shutdown -r now</title><link href="http://gavin.carothers.name/shutdown-r-now.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-07-14T20:42:00-07:00</updated><author><name>gavin</name></author><id>tag:gavin.carothers.name,2009-07-14:shutdown-r-now.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Running the most recent Ubuntu builds leads to odd things happening from
time to time. This mornings little bit of joy was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
-bash: shutdown: command not found
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that somewhere in the last &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;aptitude &lt;span class="pre"&gt;dist-upgrade&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; the
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;upstart&lt;/tt&gt; package had been dropped from the selected list. For those
wondering upstart provides a large number of the functions need for
init.d, and the general run level management process. There used to be a
package for systemv level compatibility where shutdown binaries lived,
that package no longer existed. Simple solution in the end, just install
upstart again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I bring this up on the blog? Well, it was time to restart the
blog again. See a few weeks ago I upgraded it too, to WordPress 2.8.1,
or rather WordPress thought it upgraded itself to 2.8.1. What really
happened is it completely broke itself to the point that it wasn't even
logging any errors. This is a nice clean fresh install of WordPress
2.8.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do love upgrading software on computers, always thrilling.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>gc.isenabled() == True</title><link href="http://gavin.carothers.name/gc-isenabled-true.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-01-17T20:25:00-08:00</updated><author><name>gavin</name></author><id>tag:gavin.carothers.name,2009-01-17:gc-isenabled-true.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe the 7th try is the charm. This will be at least my 7th blog
like entity. Perhaps this time it will go better. Other blogging
attempts have been, “The Flickering Fluorescent”, DNS lapsed.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gjc314159.livejournal.com/"&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt;, which has been
updated a grand total of 3 times… in 7 years. I’m sure there were other
ones, I remember creating the themes and setting them up, don’t remember
much else about them. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/gcarothers"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; has
been going better, but then it’s not really a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal, I think within reason, is to post here at least once a week. Of
course just at the moment this blog doesn’t seem to be off to an
auspicious start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
host gavin.carothers.name
;; connection timed out; no servers could be reached
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah well, have to start some where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
echo '8.17.170.105 gavin.carothers.name' &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/hosts
&lt;/pre&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>